provident.com 2015-03-25

# Privacy - Provident Funding

**_Here at Provident Funding, our continued focus on loan quality and customer service is never separate from our commitment to protect the privacy and security of those who visit us at www.provident.com. For this reason we have put together the following policy to explain just how we protect and use the information collected by us, or provided by you, through our website._**

Provident Funding Associates, L.P. 

You may visit and use certain features of our site without providing personal information necessary to register with us. Our Rate Calculator, Amortization Charts, and general information about us or our programs/offers fall under this category.

However, existing or former Provident Funding customers, wishing to access their account or other non-public information on our site will need to register by creating a username and password. To register, you are required to provide your e-mail address, loan or application number, property zip code, and your social security number for identification purposes. 

If you are applying for a loan on our site, you will need to complete a loan application by providing necessary personally identifiable information, including contact, property, employment, income, assets and liabilities information, as well as various additional demographic information and declarations. 

Whether you are a new or an existing customer, the information you provide allows us to establish a user profile so that we may customize your preferences, send you the information that you desire and establish security measures to ensure that only you, and those with your authorization, have access to your account.  
It also allows you, as a customer, to securely perform the following functions: Access your loan information; upload documentation for a new loan in progress or currently serviced loan; as well as enter bank account related information for appraisal deposits or Automatic Monthly Payments (ACH) set-up. 

It also allows us to provide a faster method for you to submit and receive information to and from Provident Funding. We may also use your computer's IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to otherwise administer our site, as well as to gather broad aggregated demographic information such as the number of visitors from a particular geographic area. 

The internet is comprised of many different networks and systems that are unprotected and outside of Provident Funding’s administrative control. Because of this, we advise our customers and visitors to always exercise caution when browsing any site on the internet. Since website security is a very high priority for us, our company has implemented several internet safeguards and secure customer tools to ensure that we are providing you with the highest level of available privacy when using our website: 

  * Personal information that is stored on our secured servers is protected against unauthorized access through the use of industry standard security products and networks. As an additional layer of security, our servers are only accessible to a limited number of employees who have acknowledged our security policy and procedures and obtained special access rights to these systems. 
  * All sensitive information supplied by you will be transmitted and protected via a combination of Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption software and the HTTPS protocol. Together, these two features protect you by encrypting and authenticating your data communication with our website. 
  * As an additional security benefit to our registered users, Provident Funding has created several technological amenities aimed at increasing the protection of your personal information. One benefit that we have created for our registered users is the option to directly upload loan related documentation through your online account. This is the most secure method of sending documents to us since traditional email and fax transmission is not protected by security features including SSL encryption or HTTPS protocol. For the best possible protection of your private information, we recommend using these tools for your ultimate benefit.

To ensure compliance with updated security technology, Provident Funding recommends that you use one of the following browsers which can be downloaded free of charge: 

To ensure the highest level of security available today, Provident Funding suggests that you choose the 128-bit encryption and most updated browser version from the download options. If you do not have access to a browser that supports at least 48-bit encryption, your information may not be processed by our servers, or may not be securely transferred through your web browser to our servers. 

Provident Funding may share the non-public information of our current and former customers for the purpose of our, and our affiliates, everyday business or marketing purposes. This does not apply to those customers who are only visitors to our site and who have never registered and obtained a user name and password. 

During the loan process, or after, you may receive phone calls or mail based solicitations from other companies offering financial products or solutions that you did not directly request such as: Credit Card offers, refinancing offers, or other financing related offers. This occurs because credit reporting agencies are permitted to share your information and credit request with these companies whenever you apply for a home loan. In order to stop these calls and solicitations you can “opt-out” by calling (888) 567-8688 or completing a form at www.optoutprescreen.com 

Do Not Track (DNT) functionality is an optional browser support mechanism that allows users to select whether they want to opt-out of website tracking or not. At this time, Provident Funding does not honor Do Not Track Requests. To opt out of affiliate based sharing of your personal information please log in to your online account and select “Forms” from the “My Account” section to print an opt-out notice. 

Cookies are bits of electronic information that a website can transfer to a visitor's hard drive to help to tailor and keep records of his or her visit to the site. Cookies allow website operators to better customize visits to the site based on the visitor's preferences. The use of cookies is standard on the Internet and many websites use them. Although most web browsers automatically accept cookies you can usually change your browser to prevent or notify you whenever you are sent a cookie. This gives you an opportunity to decide whether or not to accept it. Even without accepting a cookie you can still access most of the features on our site. We use cookies so that we can provide our customers and registered users with a better and more efficient experience on our site as well as to provide for a faster method of logging-in to your account. We suggest that you visit [http://www.cookiecentral.com](http://www.cookiecentral.com/) if you would like more information about cookies. 

www.provident.com is specifically a financial services website that does not contain any content directed to children under the age of 13. However, to the extent that any child under the age of 13 enters our site, pursuant to the provisions of the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA), we are not permitted, and therefore do not, collect any personally identifiable information from any child that we actually know to be under thirteen years of age without the consent of that child's parent or legal guardian. 

After registering on our site, Provident Funding allows you to modify certain portions of your personal information by any of the following avenues: 

  * Submitting a request to update information through your online account
  * Contacting us directly at 1-800-696-8199

If you wish to make updates or modifications to your phone number and/or mailing address, simply log into your online account and click “My Profile” followed by “Contact Info”. Clicking “Edit” will allow you to update this information. All updates are subject to verification to ensure the security and integrity of your account. You may be requested to provide documentation to support any allowable change requested. 

Provident Funding may choose various third party websites to link to and from, and directly display on, its own site to provide increased value to you. We may also participate in co-branding and other relationships to offer you valuable information, programs and other services and features. However, Provident Funding has no control over these linked sites as each of them will have separate privacy and data collection practices independent of ours regardless of affiliation. 

Data collected by our co-brand partners or third party websites, even if it is offered on or through our site, is not received, stored, or used in any way by us. As such, we have no responsibility or liability for these independent policies or actions and are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of any such websites. These linked sites are only for your convenience and you access them at your own risk. Nonetheless, Provident Funding seeks to protect the integrity of its website, and the links placed upon it, and we therefore request your feedback on our website and any that we link to as well (including if a specific link does not work). 

You consent to the collection and use of information by Provident Funding, as set forth in this Privacy Statement, by using our website. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page so that you will always be aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what limited circumstances we may disclose it. Continued access or use of the website shall constitute your express acceptance of any modifications to this Privacy Statement. 

Contact Us

Provident Funding welcomes your questions, comments and concerns about our privacy practices. Click here to contact our customer service representatives. 

**Effective Date:** This policy was last revised on 10/1/2014 and takes effect immediately and is in effect until further revised.
